<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-04T16:14:30+08:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll Paginate V2!</title><link href="/2016/11/welcome-to-jekyll-paginate-v2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll Paginate V2!" /><published>2016-11-28T02:16:49+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-28T02:16:49+08:00</updated><id>/2016/11/welcome-to-jekyll-paginate-v2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/welcome-to-jekyll-paginate-v2.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. This post along with all of the other example posts is paginated by the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2 gem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pagination gem is built specially for Jekyll 3 and newer and is intended to replace the now discontinuted jekyll-paginate gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This v2 of the gem offers full backwards compatibility with the old gem and its site configuration. You can simply replace the old jekyll-paginate gem with this one and your sites will still work without any changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However to access the new enhanced features of this gem, like pagination on categories, tags and locales, then you need to remove the old jekyll-paginate configuration and activate the new &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pagination:&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2#site-configuration&quot;&gt;site configuration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2/tree/master/examples&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; for this example project will show you all the necessary steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing&quot;&gt;Installing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and install the latest version of the gem from &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubygems.org/gems/jekyll-paginate-v2&quot;&gt;rubygems.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install jekyll-paginate-v2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replace the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate&lt;/code&gt; gem with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/code&gt; in both your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; and your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go ahead and re-build your site to start running the new pagination logic. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to get the most out of this new pagination gem. There we also discuss the gems more advanced features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please file all bugs/feature requests in the issues section of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2/issues&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great day :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="paginate" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. This post along with all of the other example posts is paginated by the new jekyll-paginate-v2 gem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Columbia River</title><link href="/2016/11/columbia-river.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Columbia River" /><published>2016-11-27T02:16:49+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-27T02:16:49+08:00</updated><id>/2016/11/columbia-river</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/columbia-river.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Columbia River&lt;/strong&gt; is the largest river in the &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Pacific_Northwest&quot; title=&quot;Pacific Northwest&quot;&gt;Pacific Northwest&lt;/a&gt; region of North America.&lt;sup&gt;[[9]]&lt;/sup&gt; The river &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Headwater&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Headwater&quot;&gt;rises&lt;/a&gt; in the [Rocky Mountains] of [British Columbia], Canada. It flows northwest and then south into the US state of [Washington], then turns west to form most of the border between Washington and the state of [Oregon] before emptying into the Pacific Ocean. The river is 1,243 miles (2,000 km) long, and its largest [tributary] is the [Snake River]. Its [drainage basin] is roughly the size of France and extends into seven US states and a Canadian province.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By volume, the Columbia is the fourth-largest river in the United States; it has the greatest flow of any North American river draining into the Pacific. The river’s heavy flow and relatively steep &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Grade_(slope)&quot; title=&quot;Grade (slope)&quot;&gt;gradient&lt;/a&gt; gives it tremendous potential for the generation of electricity. The &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/List_of_dams_in_the_Columbia_River_watershed&quot; title=&quot;List of dams in the Columbia River watershed&quot;&gt;14 hydroelectric dams&lt;/a&gt; on the Columbia’s &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Main_stem&quot; title=&quot;Main stem&quot;&gt;main stem&lt;/a&gt; and many more on its tributaries produce more than 44% of total U.S. &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Hydroelectricity&quot; title=&quot;Hydroelectricity&quot;&gt;hydroelectric generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[[10]]&lt;/sup&gt; – much more hydroelectric power than those of any other North American river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Columbia and its tributaries have been central to the region’s culture and economy for thousands of years. They have been used for transportation since ancient times, linking the many cultural groups of the region. The river system hosts many species of &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Anadromous&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Anadromous&quot;&gt;anadromous&lt;/a&gt; fish, which migrate between &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Freshwater&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Freshwater&quot;&gt;freshwater&lt;/a&gt; habitats and the &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Saline_water&quot; title=&quot;Saline water&quot;&gt;saline&lt;/a&gt; waters of the Pacific Ocean. These fish—especially the &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Salmon&quot; title=&quot;Salmon&quot;&gt;salmon&lt;/a&gt; species—provided the core subsistence for native peoples; in past centuries, Indigenous peoples traveled across western North America to the Columbia to trade for fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 18th century, a private American ship became the first non-indigenous vessel to enter the river; it was followed by a British explorer, who navigated past the &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Oregon_Coast_Range&quot; title=&quot;Oregon Coast Range&quot;&gt;Oregon Coast Range&lt;/a&gt; into the &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Willamette_Valley&quot; title=&quot;Willamette Valley&quot;&gt;Willamette Valley&lt;/a&gt;. In the following decades, &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Fur_trade&quot; title=&quot;Fur trade&quot;&gt;fur trading&lt;/a&gt; companies used the Columbia as a key transportation route. Overland explorers entered the Willamette Valley through the scenic but treacherous &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Columbia_River_Gorge&quot; title=&quot;Columbia River Gorge&quot;&gt;Columbia River Gorge&lt;/a&gt;, and pioneers began to settle the valley in increasing numbers, following both routes to enter it. &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Steamship&quot; title=&quot;Steamship&quot;&gt;Steamships&lt;/a&gt; along the river linked communities and facilitated trade; the arrival of railroads in the late 19th century, many running along the river, supplemented these links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[[10]]: #cite_note-IEA2014-10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[[9]]: #cite_note-9
  [Rocky Mountains]: /wiki/Rocky_Mountains “Rocky Mountains”
  [British Columbia]: /wiki/British_Columbia “British Columbia”
  [Washington]: /wiki/Washington_(state) “Washington (state)”
  [Oregon]: /wiki/Oregon “Oregon”
  [tributary]: /wiki/Tributary “Tributary”
  [Snake River]: /wiki/Snake_River “Snake River”
  [drainage basin]: /wiki/Drainage_basin “Drainage basin”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="wikipedia" /><summary type="html">From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Télé 7 Jours</title><link href="/2016/11/tele7jours.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Télé 7 Jours" /><published>2016-11-26T02:16:49+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-26T02:16:49+08:00</updated><id>/2016/11/tele7jours</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/tele7jours.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Télé 7 Jours&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/French_language&quot; title=&quot;French language&quot;&gt;French&lt;/a&gt; weekly magazine published by &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Hachette_Filipacchi_M%C3%A9dias&quot; title=&quot;Hachette Filipacchi Médias&quot;&gt;Hachette Filipacchi Médias&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/France&quot; title=&quot;France&quot;&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;. It publishes news and materials relating to French radio and television programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;history-and-profile&quot;&gt;History and profile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, the magazine was named “Radio 44” as it started publishing on 29 October 1944. The name would change (“Radio 45”, “Radio 46”, etc.) as the year of publication changed, until the year 1957, when it was renamed “Radio Télévision 57” and in 1959 was changed to “Télé 59”. Its contents are basically coverage of television news and listings, cultural and lifestyle news and entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1960, Sofirad, the original owner, sold the magazine to &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Jean_Prouvost&quot; title=&quot;Jean Prouvost&quot;&gt;Jean Prouvost&lt;/a&gt;, who named it “7 jours Télé 60” for a short period and then renamed it to the present “Télé 7 Jours” from 7 March 1960.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magazine is published on a weekly basis.&lt;sup&gt;[[1]]&lt;/sup&gt; Its circulation jumped to more than a million copies weekly in 1962 and 2 million by 1965 becoming the biggest circulation weekly in France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1976, &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/Hachette_Filipacchi_M%C3%A9dias&quot; title=&quot;Hachette Filipacchi Médias&quot;&gt;Hachette&lt;/a&gt; purchased the magazine.&lt;sup&gt;[[2]]&lt;/sup&gt; The magazine remained the most read French magazine in the 1980s and 1990s reaching a circulation of 3.2 million weekly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1985 to 2003, &lt;em&gt;Télé 7 Jours&lt;/em&gt; organized a &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/French_television&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;French television&quot;&gt;French television&lt;/a&gt; production award (similar in nature to the [Emmy Awards]) called the &lt;em&gt;[7 d’Or]&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;[[2]]&lt;/sup&gt; From 1996 to 1999, [Benjamin Cuq] worked as reporter for &lt;em&gt;Télé 7 Jours&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;circulation&quot;&gt;Circulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Télé 7 Jours had a circulation of 2,800,000 copies in 1974.[3] The circulation of the weekly was 2,606,000 copies in 1999.[4]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the sixth best-selling television magazine worldwide with a circulation of 2,371,000 copies during in 2001.[1] In 2005 its circulation dropped to 1,892,000 copies, but it was the best-selling magazine in France.[5]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circulation of the magazine was 1,588,000 copies during the 2007-2008 period.[6] In 2010 the magazine had a circulation of 1,471,593 copies.[7] Its circulation was 1,225,642 copies in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[[1]]: #cite_note-mags-1
  [[2]]: #cite_note-rich-2
  [Emmy Awards]: /wiki/Emmy_Award “Emmy Award”
  [7 d’Or]: /wiki/7_d%27Or “7 d’Or”
  [Benjamin Cuq]: /wiki/Benjamin_Cuq “Benjamin Cuq”
  [1]: /w/index.php?title=T%C3%A9l%C3%A9_7_Jours&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;section=2 “Edit section: Circulation”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="wikipedia" /><summary type="html">From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Narcisse Snake Pits</title><link href="/2016/11/narcisse-snake-pits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Narcisse Snake Pits" /><published>2016-11-25T02:16:49+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-25T02:16:49+08:00</updated><id>/2016/11/narcisse-snake-pits</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/narcisse-snake-pits.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Narcisse Snake Pits are located in the Rural Municipality of Armstrong about 6 kilometres (3.7 mi) north of Narcisse, Manitoba, Canada. The dens are the winter home of tens of thousands of red-sided garter snakes (Thamnophis sirtalis parietalis). These pits are the largest concentration in the world of this particular type of snake. Their winter dens are subterranean caverns formed by the area’s water-worn limestone bedrock. In the spring, they come up from their dens to the snake pits, where they engage in mating rituals. Then they disperse into the nearby marshes for the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conservation&quot;&gt;Conservation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population of red-sided garter snakes around Narcisse was roughly 70,000 until terrible weather in 1999 killed tens of thousands of them before they could reach their winter dens. [1] This tragedy triggered concern about the snakes’ biannual migratory path, which cuts right across Highway 17. Every year, ten thousand snakes trying to get to or from their winter dens had been crushed under the wheels of vehicles. This had not been a problem before, because the vast population compensated for the losses. After the winter of 1999, however, the population of garter snakes was dangerously low, causing Manitoba Hydro and volunteers to intervene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foot-high snow fences were built to force snakes into six-inch (15-cm) tunnels that went under Highway 17. Since some snakes still managed to squeeze under the fence and onto the road, signs were put up during the migratory season urging motorists to slow down to avoid accidentally driving over snakes. These measures worked, and now less than a thousand snakes per season are killed on the highway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visiting&quot;&gt;Visiting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conservation area is open to the public. The snakes are most active during the spring and fall - in late April to early May, which is the mating season, and also in early September, when the snakes slither back down to their winter dens.[1]&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="wikipedia" /><summary type="html">From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Luft-Fahrzeug-Gesellschaft</title><link href="/2016/11/luft-fahrzeug-gesellschaft.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Luft-Fahrzeug-Gesellschaft" /><published>2016-11-24T02:16:49+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-24T02:16:49+08:00</updated><id>/2016/11/luft-fahrzeug-gesellschaft</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/luft-fahrzeug-gesellschaft.html">&lt;p&gt;Luft-Fahrzeug-Gesellschaft, also referred to as LFG, was a German aircraft manufacturer during World War I. They are best known for their various “Roland” designs, notably the Roland C.II Walfisch (whale), Roland D.II haifisch (Shark) and Roland D.VI, although they also produced a number of airships and many experimental designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;airships&quot;&gt;Airships&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luft-Fahrzeug-Gesellschaft formed on April 30, 1908, from the assets of an experimental airship engine company located in Bitterfeld, Motorluftschiff Studiengesellscaft (MStG). Additional funding for the new enterprise was provided primarily by Krupp, AEG, and a local chemical company. The company’s offices were located in Berlin along with the factory at Adlershof. Manufacture was transferred to Charlottenburg following a fire on 6 September 1916, allegedly caused by the British Secret Service.[1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their first project was an airship design by August von Parseval, a German airship designer. This entered service as the PL.II in 1910. During World War I, four were delivered to the German Army and Navy. In total some 25 “PL” airships were built, flown and delivered to various customers. The PL-26, one of the last, crashed on landing and burnt inside hangar Luftschiffhalle 2 with no fatalities. For the rest of the war the hangars were used mostly for repairs of observation balloons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aeroplanes&quot;&gt;Aeroplanes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1913 LFG started producing new designs under the trade name Roland to avoid confusion with the Luftverkehrsgesellschaft (L.V.G.) firm. In 1916 the company developed a floatplane version of the Albatros C.Ia as the LFG W. Some parts were built in Bitterfeld, but final assembly and checkout was carried out in new factories in Stralsund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their first successful design was the Roland C.II Walfisch (whale), a two-seat reconnaissance biplane. It had a semi-monocoque fuselage, skinned with two layers of long plywood strips glued at opposing diagonal angles around a mold and skinned with fabric both inside and outside. The fuselage filled the full gap between the wings, leaving the pilot and observer/gunner over the top wings with an excellent view upward. The fuselage “half-shells” were each fitted onto a supporting framework of wooden formers and longerons. The “wrapping” technique of the long plywood strips for the outer fuselage surface led to this particular technique of manufacture being described in German as the Wickelrumpf (wrapped body) style of construction, and was subsequently patented by the firm,[2] licensing the construction method to Pfalz in 1917 for construction of their own single-seat fighter designs. Although it was said to have tricky handling, the Roland C.II had excellent performance, and was also used on long-range missions as a bomber escort. A version with the 200 hp Benz Bz.IV engine and new wing struts was built as the D.III, but only one prototype was ever built, as was the case for the 160 hp Mercedes D.III-powered C.V.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The C.II was adapted to the pure fighter role as the Roland D.I, but in this role the poor forward view proved to be a problem. A fire at the factory severely constrained production, and only 20 were built. A newer version with a more conventional layout, the Roland D.II, followed, whose fuselage was reduced in height to leave a gap with the upper wing but was otherwise similar overall. The competing Albatros D.I was preferred, and only about 230 examples were built, which where then mostly used on the eastern front and in Macedonia. The fuselage to wing gap was further increased in the D.III, but the temperamental 180 hp Argus As.III limited production to only a handful. Six D.IIs were delivered in July 1917 to the Bulgarian Air Force, and six D.IIIs were delivered in May 1918.[3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the Wickelrumpf style of wood-structure monocoque fuselage was extremely strong, it was also very difficult and time-consuming to build. A new method of construction was introduced that used spruce planking running the length of the aircraft in place of the formed plywood, and the D.III was adapted using this technique to produce D.IV triplane and D.V biplane, both powered by the D.III’s 160 hp Mercedes. The fuselage shell’s construction technique for these aircraft resembled a clinker-planked boat hull in appearance when finished, and was named Klinkerrumpf (clinker body) construction, and was also patented by the firm.[4] A further adaptation of the D.IV with the 185 hp Benz Bz. III resulted in the Roland D.VI, which was entered in the First Fighter Competition trials at Adlershof in early 1918. Although the Fokker D.VII won that contest, the D.VI was also ordered into production as it used a different engine, and by the end of the war about 350 had been delivered. A large number of different versions using various engines were built as prototypes without entering production, as well as a triplane adaptation as the D.VI (also known as the Dr.I).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next major design from Roland were parasol monoplane designs, the D.XVI with the Siemens-Halske Sh.III or 170 hp Goebel Goe.IIIa rotary piston engines, and the otherwise similar D.XVII with the inline 185 hp BMW IIIa. Both were entered into the Second Fighter Competition at Adlershof, but lost to the Fokker D.VIII.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the war all aircraft production in Germany was banned, and the company was forced to close the Bitterfeld plant and reopen in Seddin, producing airplanes, balloons and life boats. In 1933, aircraft production shut down. Three additional Parseval pattern airships were also built during this period.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="wikipedia" /><summary type="html">Luft-Fahrzeug-Gesellschaft, also referred to as LFG, was a German aircraft manufacturer during World War I. They are best known for their various “Roland” designs, notably the Roland C.II Walfisch (whale), Roland D.II haifisch (Shark) and Roland D.VI, although they also produced a number of airships and many experimental designs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rotary engine</title><link href="/2016/11/rotary-engine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rotary engine" /><published>2016-11-23T02:16:49+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-23T02:16:49+08:00</updated><id>/2016/11/rotary-engine</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/rotary-engine.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rotary engine was an early type of internal-combustion engine, usually designed with an odd number of cylinders per row in a radial configuration, in which the crankshaft remained stationary in operation, with the entire crankcase and its attached cylinders rotating around it as a unit. Its main application was in aviation, although it also saw use before its primary aviation role, in a few early motorcycles and automobiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of engine was widely used as an alternative to conventional inline engines (straight or V) during World War I and the years immediately preceding that conflict. It has been described as “a very efficient solution to the problems of power output, weight, and reliability”.[1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the early 1920s, however, the inherent limitations of this type of engine had rendered it obsolete, with the power output increasingly going into overcoming the air-resistance of the spinning engine itself. The rotating mass of the engine also caused significant gyroscopic precession: depending on the type of aircraft, this produced stability and control problems, especially for inexperienced pilots. Another factor in the demise of the rotary was the fundamentally inefficient total-loss oiling system, caused by the need to aspirate the fuel/air mixture through the hollow crankshaft and crankcase along with the lubricating medium, as in a two-stroke engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rotary engine is essentially a standard Otto cycle engine, but instead of having a fixed cylinder block with rotating crankshaft as with a conventional radial engine, the crankshaft remains stationary and the entire cylinder block rotates around it. In the most common form, the crankshaft was fixed solidly to the airframe, and the propeller was simply bolted to the front of the crankcase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three key factors contributed to the rotary engine’s success at the time:[2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smooth running: Rotaries delivered power very smoothly because (relative to the engine mounting point) there are no reciprocating parts, and the relatively large rotating mass of the crankcase/cylinders (as a unit) acted as a flywheel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved cooling: when the engine was running the rotating crankcase/cylinder assembly created its own fast-moving cooling airflow, even with the aircraft at rest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight advantage: many conventional engines had to have heavy flywheels added to smooth out power impulses and reduce vibration. Rotary engines gained a substantial power-to-weight ratio advantage by having no need for an added flywheel. They shared with other radial configuration engines the advantage of a small, flat crankcase, and because of their efficient air-cooling system cylinders could be made with thinner walls and shallower cooling fins, which further reduced their weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most rotary engines were arranged with the cylinders pointing outwards from a single crankshaft, in the same general form as a radial, but there were also rotary boxer engines[3] and even one-cylinder rotaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like radial engines, rotaries were generally built with an odd number of cylinders (usually either 7 or 9), so that a consistent every-other-piston firing order could be maintained, to provide smooth running. Rotary engines with an even number of cylinders were mostly of the “two row” type.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="wikipedia" /><summary type="html">From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sailing at the 1988 Summer Olympics</title><link href="/2016/11/sailing-summer-olympics-1988.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sailing at the 1988 Summer Olympics" /><published>2016-11-22T02:16:49+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T02:16:49+08:00</updated><id>/2016/11/sailing-summer-olympics-1988</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/sailing-summer-olympics-1988.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sailing/Yachting is an Olympic sport starting from the 1896 Olympics in Athens, Greece). With the exception of 1904 and possible 1916 sailing was always a part of the Olympic program. The Sailing program of 1988 consisted of a total of eight sailing classes (disciplines). For each class seven races were scheduled from September 20, 1988 to September 27, 1988 of the coast of Busan and was the first time that a separate event was allocated exclusively for women (sailed in the 470 class). The sailing was done on the triangular type Olympic courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;venue&quot;&gt;Venue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the IOC statutes the contests in all sport disciplines must be held either in, or as close as possible to the city which the IOC has chosen. Since the sailing conditions of the coast near Seoul are not very suitable for Olympic sailing Busan was chosen for the 1988 Sailing event. A total of two race areas were created of the coast of Busan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Busan in Korea was reportedly a light wind venue but no one realised until too late that this information came from the airport which was located in a sheltered valley. It turned out to be that the 1988 Olympic Games were one of the windiest ever with one day of racing postponed due to too much wind. One day of racing saw around 30 knots of wind with 5 knots of current going against the wind. There was a lot of equipment damage and rescues for many classes resulting in many sailors did not finish and requests for redress.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="wikipedia" /><summary type="html">From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Geography of Minneapolis</title><link href="/2016/11/geography-of-minneapolis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Geography of Minneapolis" /><published>2016-11-21T02:16:49+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-21T02:16:49+08:00</updated><id>/2016/11/geography-of-minneapolis</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/geography-of-minneapolis.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minneapolis is the largest city in the state of Minnesota in the United States, and the county seat of Hennepin County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;physical&quot;&gt;Physical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the United States Census Bureau, the city has a total area of 151.3 km² (58.4 mi²). 142.2 km² (54.9 mi²) of it is land and 9.1 km² (3.5 mi²) of it (6.01%) is water. The city center is located just south of 45 degrees north latitude. On the south side of Golden Valley Road just east of Wirth Parkway, a stone containing a weathered plaque marks a point on the 45th parallel.[1] The Mississippi, which runs to the southeast, directed the early growth of the city. Most early streets ran parallel to the river to maximize the amount of land that could be used. Eventually, growth of Minneapolis turned to north-south and east-west streets. Many unique intersections like Seven Corners on the eastern periphery of downtown were formed to translate between the two layouts. Some streets, especially older and more traditionally important ones like Hennepin Avenue and Nicollet Avenue, have both orientations at different points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;parks-and-lakes&quot;&gt;Parks and lakes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minneapolis has a large park system consisting of ten square miles (26 km²) of land and water that is interlinked in many places. Theodore Wirth is often credited with the development of this system that brought a playground within the reach of most children and the canopy of trees and boulevards in much of the city. The Mississippi National River and Recreation Area connects regional parks and visitors centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theodore Wirth Park is the largest in the city, shared with Golden Valley, and is about 60% the size of Central Park in New York City. Minnehaha Park is one of the most famous, the site of Minnehaha Falls and cultural heritage events every year. Tower Hill Park in Prospect Park is the home of a 1913 water tower, one of the highest points in Minneapolis.[2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grand Rounds Scenic Byway circles through the city and many of the larger park areas including land along the Mississippi, lakes and scenic areas. A parkway for cars, a bikeway for riders, and a walkway for pedestrians run parallel paths along the 50-mile route. A growing number of bikeways and walkways crisscross the city and interconnect with neighboring cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty four small lakes are within the city limits.[3] Among the largest freshwater lakes to the west are Lake Harriet, Lake Calhoun, Lake of the Isles, and Cedar Lake, known together as the “Chain of Lakes”. Lake Nokomis and Lake Hiawatha are to the east. Connected by bike, running and walking paths, Minneapolis lakes are used for swimming, fishing, picnics and boating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flora-and-fauna&quot;&gt;Flora and fauna&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;waterfalls&quot;&gt;Waterfalls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area now occupied by the Twin Cities generally consisted of a 155 foot (47 m) thick layer of St. Peter Sandstone, under a 16 foot (5 m) thick layer of shale, under a 35 foot (11 m) thick layer of Platteville limestone.[4] These layers were the result of an Ordovician Period sea which covered east-central Minnesota 500 million years ago.[4] The hard limestone cap was formed from fossilized shell fish. About 20,000 years ago, the area was covered by the Superior Lobe of the Laurentide ice sheet, which left the St. Croix moraine on the Twin Cities as it receded.[4] Later the Grantsburg Sublobe of the Des Moines Lobe also covered the area.[5] Under these vast layers of ice, tunnel valleys were formed, cutting through the limestone layer with tremendous force, to release ice meltwater and glacier effluence.[6] The result was a series of troughs in the limestone, which were filled by glacial till and outwash deposit as the glaciers receded. Sometimes the sediment would be mixed with huge chunks of ice, which would leave voids in the soil. These voids created basins for the Twin Cities Lakes, such as Harriet and Lake Calhoun.[6] Connecting the city lakes in several north-south arteries are gorges cut through the bedrock, but filled with sand and sediment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When River Warren Falls receded past the confluence of the much smaller Upper Mississippi River, a new waterfall was created where that river entered the much-lower glacial River Warren. The new falls also receded upstream on the Mississippi, migrating eight miles (12875 m) over 9600 years to where Louis Hennepin first saw it and named St. Anthony Falls in 1680. Due to its value as a power source, this waterfall determined the location of Minneapolis. One branch of the river coming from the west, Minnehaha Creek receded only a few hundred yards from one of the channels of the Mississippi. Minnehaha Falls remains as a picturesque and informative relic of River Warren Falls, and the limestone-over-sandstone construction is readily apparent in its small gorge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="wikipedia" /><summary type="html">From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</summary></entry></feed>